<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Comrade&#39;s Conscience ☭</title>
    <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Comrade&#39;s Conscience ☭</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://comradesconscience.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One year later: what January 6th tells us about Democrats&#39; inaction [Part 2]</title>
      <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/2022-01-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/2022-01-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Democratic Party is, unfortunately, best characterized in the present-day, as a party of ineptitude, apathy, and inaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following an attempted coup led by Trump to overturn an election, which jeopardized the lives of Democratic (and Republican) politicians, the party controlling the White House and both chambers of Congress, has failed to seek serious legal actions or legislative policies to condemn the attacks and prevent future assaults on its sovereignty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, Nancy Pelosi, the Democratic Speaker of the House, introduced Lin Manuel Miranda and the cast of &amp;ldquo;Hamilton&amp;rdquo; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://thehill.com/blogs/in-the-know/in-the-know/588608-hamilton-creator-lin-manuel-miranda-cast-members-participate-in&#34;&gt;perform&lt;/a&gt; at a commemorative event marking the one year anniversary of the Capitol riots. This performative gesture bore a troubling resemblance to the stunt pulled during the summer of 2020 when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-52978780&#34;&gt;Democrats wore Ghana&amp;rsquo;s kente cloth and took a symbolic knee&lt;/a&gt; following the murder of George Floyd. This was a boring attempt at cultural appropriation and wokeness political theater with effectively no material change in people&amp;rsquo;s lives. As one activist put it, followed by a telling Twitter thread:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
      .twitter-tweet {
        font: 14px/1.45 -apple-system,BlinkMacSystemFont,&#34;Segoe UI&#34;,Roboto,Oxygen-Sans,Ubuntu,Cantarell,&#34;Helvetica Neue&#34;,sans-serif;
        border-left: 4px solid #2b7bb9;
        padding-left: 1.5em;
        color: #555;
      }
      .twitter-tweet a {
        color: #2b7bb9;
        text-decoration: none;
      }
      blockquote.twitter-tweet a:hover,
      blockquote.twitter-tweet a:focus {
        text-decoration: underline;
      }
    &lt;/style&gt;
  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Performative opposition is the raison dêtre of the Democratic Party. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/7HV3oLzwPA&#34;&gt;https://t.co/7HV3oLzwPA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Peter Daou (@peterdaou) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/peterdaou/status/1479268097634750465?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 7, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Democrats claim to support Black Americans during election cycles but fail to cancel student debt, which is estimated to increase the wealth of Black Americans by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/korihale/2021/12/14/the-85-billion-student-loan-payment-restart-weighs-on-racial-wealth-gap/?sh=74c983031a9c&#34;&gt;40%&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They claim to be the party that acknowledge climate change, yet famously fail to take any meaningful action to reverse the course of ecological destruction. Instead, Democrats from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2019/feb/22/dianne-feinstein-sunrise-movement-green-new-deal&#34;&gt;California&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/20/us/politics/manchin-climate-change-coal.html&#34;&gt;West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; routinely dismiss calls to action from climate activists. Despite resuming public appearances at climate summits following Trump&amp;rsquo;s 4-year hiatus from such events, Joe Biden continues in the American tradition of faux progressivism: to protect capitalistic interests, Biden simultaneously presents himself as a champion of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/17/opinion/biden-climate-change.html&#34;&gt;environmentalism&lt;/a&gt; while remaining strangely obsessed with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/joe-biden-suddenly-loves-frackers-oil-industry-11634336080&#34;&gt;fracking&lt;/a&gt; and continues allowing sales of large swaths of land for offshore fossil fuel extraction to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newsweek.com/joe-biden-oil-environment-gas-drilling-gulf-mexico-climate-change-1650202&#34;&gt;proceed&lt;/a&gt;. Surprising no one paying attention, the moderate climate policies the Biden administration and &amp;ldquo;progressives&amp;rdquo; in Congress pushed for were pulled out from the recently passed bipartisan infrastructure &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/aug/12/is-biden-serious-about-climate-his-2000-drilling-and-fracking-permits-suggest-not&#34;&gt;bill&lt;/a&gt; and stuffed into the &amp;ldquo;Build Back Better&amp;rdquo; bill, which has now come to a grinding halt from conservative Democrats like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/19/climate/manchin-climate-build-back-better-bill.html&#34;&gt;Joe Manchin&lt;/a&gt;, a move which anyone following his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2021/10/a-closer-look-at-joe-manchins-ties-to-the-fossil-fuel-industy/&#34;&gt;business interests&lt;/a&gt; (e.g., receiving the largest campaign contributions from fossil fuel industries out of anyone in Congress and continuing to make millions of dollars from his coal company, Enersystems) should come to expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Democrats are willing to stump against the War in Iraq as a great foreign policy blunder (to put it mildly), but will shift gears to celebrate, fawn over, and admire the infamous war criminal and former Vice President, Dick Cheney. How can anyone trust Democrats who in one breath claim to distance themselves from unnecessary and unethical warfare and then happily bask in the presence of war-mongerers, some of whom, responsible for millions of deaths, they consider to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thenation.com/article/archive/hillary-clintons-embrace-of-kissinger-is-inexcusable/&#34;&gt;friends&lt;/a&gt;, and others, who led &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2015/sep/01/dick-cheney-defends-america-torture-new-book&#34;&gt;practices of torture&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2011/08/remembering-why-americans-loathe-dick-cheney/244306/&#34;&gt;started wars under false pretenses for profit&lt;/a&gt;, they continue to cherish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were very honored by [Dick Cheney] being there. He has a right to be on the floor as a former member of the House. I was happy to welcome him back, and to congratulate him on the courage.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
— &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Rep. Nancy Pelosi&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Democrats are not going to &amp;ldquo;save democracy,&amp;rdquo; or, more accurately, protect people from fascism. They will, instead, in classic 21st century neoliberal fashion, continue &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-57589416&#34;&gt;raising police budgets&lt;/a&gt; while claiming &amp;ldquo;Black Lives Matter,&amp;rdquo; rail against endless wars but continue &lt;a href=&#34;https://time.com/6099377/afghanistan-drone-strike-counterterrorism/&#34;&gt;killing civilians abroad&lt;/a&gt; and sell hundreds of millions of dollars worth of weapons to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/us-state-dept-okays-650-million-potential-air-to-air-missile-deal-saudi-arabia-2021-11-04/&#34;&gt;Saudi Arabia&lt;/a&gt;, weapons we know are being used to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3025289/shocking-saudi-coalition-air-strike-kills-more-100-yemen?module=inline&amp;amp;pgtype=article&#34;&gt;kill humans in Yemen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, the Democratic Party is yet another capitalist party hellbent on maintaining the systems that enable them to make &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jacobinmag.com/2021/12/house-speaker-paul-stocks-insider-trading-wealth&#34;&gt;endless profits&lt;/a&gt;, even if it comes at the cost of millions suffering and hundreds of thousands dying during a global pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is to be a systemic upheaval, it will not be possible through the Democratic Party. It&amp;rsquo;s time we adjust our expectations and not delude ourselves into believing that the Democratic Party is either able or interested in preventing far-right extremism, rampant conspiratorial thinking, or undoing the centuries-old capitalistic traditions of pursuing profits above all else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2022/01/06/dick-cheney-surprise-visit-capitol-jan-6-riot/9122457002/&#34;&gt;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2022/01/06/dick-cheney-surprise-visit-capitol-jan-6-riot/9122457002/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One year later: what January 6th tells us about national (in)security [Part 1]</title>
      <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/2022-01-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/2022-01-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent the day yesterday unsure about how to think about the attempted coup on the American government that took place one year ago and, with one year since its happening, have decided to focus on the following (somewhat related) themes for a series of five posts, the first of which follows below: (1) the hollow theater of national security; (2) Trump and his actions won&amp;rsquo;t be effectively chastised by Democrats; (3) incompetence saves us again; (4) Constitutional path allows for a blatant path to subverting electors&#39; votes; and (5) motives, GOP apologists and white bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;America works hard by spending billions of dollars annually to give off the impression that it takes its national security seriously. More than anything, as we know well, this is usually used as a guise under which an overriding suspicion of &amp;ldquo;others&amp;rdquo; is harvested by demagogues and profited by the prison and military industrial complexes, without evidencing effective reductions in perceived or actual threats or harm caused to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be specific, following the 9/11 attacks, airport security infamously began to perform &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2014/01/tsa-business-security-theater-not-security/357599/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Security Theater&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; (removing shoes, disposing bottles of liquids, walking through scanners and being pat down) to create a sense of security via public optics, even though undercover tests of airport security reveal its clear ineffectiveness. For example, a 2017 undercover test &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newsweek.com/tsa-fails-half-time-706568&#34;&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; that the TSA failed to catch over 70% of weapons (e.g., mock knives, guns, etc.) that were smuggled through security, an improvement from 2015 when 95% were missed in a similar test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, while the federal government continues to increase funding for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.americanimmigrationcouncil.org/research/the-cost-of-immigration-enforcement-and-border-security&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;border security&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, the number of &amp;ldquo;migrant encounters&amp;rdquo; at the U.S.-Mexico border &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/11/09/whats-happening-at-the-u-s-mexico-border-in-7-charts/ft_21-11-01_mexicoborder_1a/&#34;&gt;peaked in 2021&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting whatever tactics employed by the Department of Homeland Security are ineffective; however, they too are meant to convince American voters that there is an ongoing crisis that is being &amp;ldquo;effectively&amp;rdquo; dealt with. While Trump&amp;rsquo;s immigration policies were openly hostile, racist, and inhumane, Biden&amp;rsquo;s are no better. Reports suggest that the number of detained migrant children has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/live/2021/03/08/us/joe-biden-news&#34;&gt;increased&lt;/a&gt; under the current administration. Kamala Harris told migrants &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-57387350&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do not come&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, even though domestic and international law &lt;a href=&#34;http://hrlr.law.columbia.edu/hrlr/enter-at-your-own-risk-criminalizing-asylum-seekers/&#34;&gt;prohibits&lt;/a&gt; denying asylum seekers without due process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a domestic note, the Philadelphia police department received &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.phillyvoice.com/philadelphia-police-tasers-funding-jim-kenney-2021-budget/&#34;&gt;$727 million&lt;/a&gt; but the department fails to solve &lt;a href=&#34;https://whyy.org/articles/philly-da-larry-krasner-gun-violence-second-term-inauguration/&#34;&gt;83% of shootings&lt;/a&gt; and there is reason to believe that this number is higher in reality given instances of incorrect and (not surprisingly) unethical &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inquirer.com/news/philadelphia-police-robert-redanauer-internal-affairs-lawsuits-arrest-20210506.html&#34;&gt;policing practices in the department&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TSA, CBP/ICE, and militarized cops do not make the country safer. But America remains obsessed with the idea of &amp;ldquo;defense,&amp;rdquo; a misnomer psychologically employed to portray Americans as victims of domestic and international threats of offensive where none or few exist. This tactic of manufacturing and leveraging irrational fears has worked: Americans are worried about being the personal victim of &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.gallup.com/poll/187688/americans-worried-terrorism-mass-shootings.aspx?g_source=Politics&amp;amp;g_medium=newsfeed&amp;amp;g_campaign=tiles&#34;&gt;terrorism&lt;/a&gt; even though the risk is greatly exaggerated and belittles humans living in countries where risk of terrorism, including from imperialist American hegemony, poses a far greater threat to a person&amp;rsquo;s sense of security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although most of this likely won&amp;rsquo;t come as a surprise, it raises an implicit question made recently on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
      .twitter-tweet {
        font: 14px/1.45 -apple-system,BlinkMacSystemFont,&#34;Segoe UI&#34;,Roboto,Oxygen-Sans,Ubuntu,Cantarell,&#34;Helvetica Neue&#34;,sans-serif;
        border-left: 4px solid #2b7bb9;
        padding-left: 1.5em;
        color: #555;
      }
      .twitter-tweet a {
        color: #2b7bb9;
        text-decoration: none;
      }
      blockquote.twitter-tweet a:hover,
      blockquote.twitter-tweet a:focus {
        text-decoration: underline;
      }
    &lt;/style&gt;
  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;U.S. HISTORY:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We said we couldn&amp;#39;t afford universal pre-k, which was proven to be an effective investment in the next generation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Meanwhile, we spent $740 billion on Defense in the same year we let domestic terrorists invade our Capitol.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Then we increased the Defense budget.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dan Price (@DanPriceSeattle) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DanPriceSeattle/status/1479134163655483392?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 6, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if the U.S. can&amp;rsquo;t manage to &amp;ldquo;defend&amp;rdquo; itself, its electoral proceedings, federal buildings, and politicians with a nearly one-trillion-dollar annual budget from a few hundred far-right insurgents, what is it able to protect? Its hegemonic rule over its people and the world&amp;rsquo;s through a marketable yet artificial creation (and subsequent management) of perceived threats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Perspective for Considering Change</title>
      <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/2021-12-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/2021-12-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to think of things being different, living under conditions that are fundamentally not the way society is currently structured. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult imagining America not being the world&amp;rsquo;s largest and most powerful state. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult imagining American politics outside of the executive, legislative, or judicial branches as they currently stand. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult for many to even entertain the thought of having more or less than 50 states in the union, 9 judges on a bench, or 270 electoral votes to reach presidential victory. But change is not only possible, but necessary for sustaining any society worth living in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps (me) to put everything into a contextual perspective, rooted in history. Consider the following facts: Homo sapiens as a species is approximately 300,000 years old, the Agricultural Revolution took place 13,000 years ago, and the Industrial Revolution only about 150 years ago. The United States and its Constitution are only 250 years old, whereas other civilizations, such as those existing in the modern-day states of China, India, Egypt, Greece, Italy, and elsewhere lasted for hundreds of years longer. The hegemonic state of American rule is not eternal, immutable, or guaranteed. But being born in America in the twenty-first century all but drives the notion into a person&amp;rsquo;s head: America is, was, and will continue to be &amp;ldquo;the greatest nation on earth&amp;rdquo; (whatever that is supposed to mean).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the U.S. then, (white) women were guaranteed the Constitutional right to vote just over one hundred years ago, Brown v. Board of Education—which found racial segregation in schools to be unconstitutional—was ruled only sixty-plus years ago, and same-sex marriages were finally federally legalized and recognized just over five years ago in Obergefell v. Hodges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state of the union is not permanent, fixed, or pre-determined. A better world is possible and a different society is attainable. And even though &amp;ldquo;the arc of the moral universe is long &amp;hellip; it bends toward justice&amp;rdquo;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, progressive change is not passively inevitable. It only comes about with struggle, struggles of the working and poor classes demanding a better world to live in and regularly makes martyrs of ordinary well-meaning humans in their unflagging pursuit of justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be told you are idealistic. That reform not revolution is the way forward. To settle for incremental, gradual change. That society is not yet ready for the grand change you propose. There are logistical barriers and you must work through the system, jump through administrative loops and bypass bureaucratic red tape. You must settle for the lesser of two evils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of this post is to motivate and invigorate. A better world is possible. And some burden of responsibility falls upon us, the privileged proletariat, to raise alarms and lift voices for our brothers and sisters for whom structural upheaval and systemic change cannot wait, for whom every bell toll saps of them life and limb. Who live in constant fear of abduction, familial separation, psychological anguish and torture, and physical abuses. For those who live under the threat of outstanding rent payments, entrenched in debts extending from student loans to medical bill payments with parasitic interest rates that keep working people trapped in a never-ending cycle of financial institutional leeches feeding off of every paycheck. Do not tell the hungry child to wait longer, the sick unhoused person to brave the elements for just another election cycle, the nurse drinking from failing water pipes and the teacher working in crumbling schools scrambling on their hands and knees to for loose dollars in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/dec/13/teachers-scramble-dollar-bills-south-dakota-dash-for-cash&#34;&gt;orchestrated spectacle&lt;/a&gt;, the workers risking their bodies under threat of virulent mutating viruses, the ones fleeing violence at school, in homes, and in their workplaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not hyperbole. Conditions will not inevitably get better. In fact, considering just the climate crisis, things will get worse. Geopolitical turmoil will boil over to a state with which human societies have not yet had to contend, from mass migrations of millions of peoples to worsening water and food scarcity to intolerable and eventually inhabitable living conditions amidst exorbitant costs to survive another week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone will be able to rocket into space to escape the ecological destruction of the planet. Jeff and Elon aren&amp;rsquo;t planning to take you with them. And it is far, far more likely that you will watch as humanity falls into the grips of its worst vices, driven by instinctual impulses to survive, than you will watching Earth fade into a pale blue dot as you sit abroad a spacecraft beaming towards an extraterrestrial planetary eden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not tell us to wait. A better world is possible. But only through collective thought and organized action. The time to act is now and there is work to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In solidarity,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.si.edu/spotlight/mlk?page=4&amp;amp;iframe=true&#34;&gt;quote&lt;/a&gt; is excerpted from Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.&amp;rsquo;s speech “Remaining Awake Through a Great Revolution” delivered at the National Cathedral, March 31, 1968.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting a (Blog) Agenda</title>
      <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/2021-12-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/2021-12-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of this blog is to track one proletariat&amp;rsquo;s developments in leftist thoughts as I continue listening, reading, learning, and growing. This is meant to serve as a platform where I might openly communicate questions and observations, with the larger goal of articulating a synthesized analysis of the current political state in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current political, economic, and social systems are structurally unsound, unjust, and unviable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is, what could or should replace it? And how might this transformation take place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before answering these questions though, I&amp;rsquo;ll start this blog from basic facts about material reality with clearly noted annotations and opinions. Some topics of interest will include American electoral politics domestically and global imperialism abroad, carceral capitalism and the militarized surveillance police states, and systems upholding racism, ecological terrorism, and patriarchal institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A larger goal of this blog is to establish what an alternative Constitution might look like, based on the working understanding that reform may be an impossible endeavor and that the proletariat struggle may be achieved by revolution alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
