<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Categories on Comrade&#39;s Conscience ☭</title>
    <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Categories on Comrade&#39;s Conscience ☭</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://comradesconscience.github.io/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting a (Blog) Agenda</title>
      <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/post1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of this blog is to track one proletariat&amp;rsquo;s developments in leftist thoughts as I continue listening, reading, learning, and growing. This is meant to serve as a platform where I might openly communicate questions and observations, with the larger goal of articulating a synthesized analysis of the current political state in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current political, economic, and social systems are structurally unsound, unjust, and unviable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is, what could or should replace it? And how might this transformation take place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before answering these questions though, I&amp;rsquo;ll start this blog from basic facts about material reality with clearly noted annotations and opinions. Some topics of interest will include American electoral politics domestically and global imperialism abroad, carceral capitalism and the militarized surveillance police states, and systems upholding racism, ecological terrorism, and patriarchal institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A larger goal of this blog is to establish what an alternative Constitution might look like, based on the working understanding that reform may be an impossible endeavor and that the proletariat struggle may be achieved by revolution alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
