<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Categories on Comrade&#39;s Conscience ☭</title>
    <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Categories on Comrade&#39;s Conscience ☭</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://comradesconscience.github.io/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Perspective for Considering Change</title>
      <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/post2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to think of things being different, living under conditions that are fundamentally not the way society is currently structured. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult imagining America not being the world&amp;rsquo;s largest and most powerful state. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult imagining American politics outside of the executive, legislative, or judicial branches as they currently stand. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult for many to even entertain the thought of having more or less than 50 states in the union, 9 judges on a bench, or 270 electoral votes to reach presidential victory. But change is not only possible, but necessary for sustaining any society worth living in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps (me) to put everything into a contextual perspective, rooted in history. Consider the following facts: Homo sapiens as a species is approximately 300,000 years old, the Agricultural Revolution took place 13,000 years ago, and the Industrial Revolution only about 150 years ago. The United States and its Constitution are only 250 years old, whereas other civilizations, such as those existing in the modern-day states of China, India, Egypt, Greece, Italy, and elsewhere lasted for hundreds of years longer. The hegemonic state of American rule is not eternal, immutable, or guaranteed. But being born in America in the twenty-first century all but drives the notion into a person&amp;rsquo;s head: America is, was, and will continue to be &amp;ldquo;the greatest nation on earth&amp;rdquo; (whatever that is supposed to mean).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the U.S. then, (white) women were guaranteed the Constitutional right to vote just over one hundred years ago, Brown v. Board of Education—which found racial segregation in schools to be unconstitutional—was ruled only sixty-plus years ago, and same-sex marriages were finally federally legalized and recognized just over five years ago in Obergefell v. Hodges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state of the union is not permanent, fixed, or pre-determined. A better world is possible and a different society is attainable. And even though &amp;ldquo;the arc of the moral universe is long &amp;hellip; it bends toward justice&amp;rdquo;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, progressive change is not passively inevitable. It only comes about with struggle, struggles of the working and poor classes demanding a better world to live in and regularly makes martyrs of ordinary well-meaning humans in their unflagging pursuit of justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be told you are idealistic. That reform not revolution is the way forward. To settle for incremental, gradual change. That society is not yet ready for the grand change you propose. There are logistical barriers and you must work through the system, jump through administrative loops and bypass bureaucratic red tape. You must settle for the lesser of two evils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of this post is to motivate and invigorate. A better world is possible. And some burden of responsibility falls upon us, the privileged proletariat, to raise alarms and lift voices for our brothers and sisters for whom structural upheaval and systemic change cannot wait, for whom every bell toll saps of them life and limb. Who live in constant fear of abduction, familial separation, psychological anguish and torture, and physical abuses. For those who live under the threat of outstanding rent payments, entrenched in debts extending from student loans to medical bill payments with parasitic interest rates that keep working people trapped in a never-ending cycle of financial institutional leeches feeding off of every paycheck. Do not tell the hungry child to wait longer, the sick unhoused person to brave the elements for just another election cycle, the failing water pipes and crumbling schools, the workers risking their bodies under threat of virulent mutating viruses, the ones fleeing violence at school, in homes, and in their dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not hyperbole. Conditions will not inevitably get better. In fact, considering just the climate crisis, things will get worse. Geopolitical turmoil will boil over to a state that human societies have not yet contended with, from mass migrations of millions of peoples to water and food scarcity to intolerable living conditions and exorbitant costs for surviving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone will be able to rocket into space to escape the ecological destruction of the planet. Jeff and Elon aren&amp;rsquo;t planning on taking you with them. And it is far, far more likely that you will watch humanity fall into our worst vices driven by instinctual impulses to survive than you will watching Earth vanish into a pale blue dot as you sit abroad a spacecraft beaming towards an extraterrestrial planetary eden for the next chapter of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not tell us to wait. A better world is possible. But only through collective thought and organized action. The time to act is now and there is work to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In solidarity,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.si.edu/spotlight/mlk?page=4&amp;amp;iframe=true&#34;&gt;quote&lt;/a&gt; is excerpted from Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.&amp;rsquo;s speech “Remaining Awake Through a Great Revolution” delivered at the National Cathedral, March 31, 1968.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting a (Blog) Agenda</title>
      <link>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://comradesconscience.github.io/posts/post1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The primary purpose of this blog is to track one proletariat&amp;rsquo;s developments in leftist thoughts as I continue listening, reading, learning, and growing. This is meant to serve as a platform where I might openly communicate questions and observations, with the larger goal of articulating a synthesized analysis of the current political state in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current political, economic, and social systems are structurally unsound, unjust, and unviable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is, what could or should replace it? And how might this transformation take place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before answering these questions though, I&amp;rsquo;ll start this blog from basic facts about material reality with clearly noted annotations and opinions. Some topics of interest will include American electoral politics domestically and global imperialism abroad, carceral capitalism and the militarized surveillance police states, and systems upholding racism, ecological terrorism, and patriarchal institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A larger goal of this blog is to establish what an alternative Constitution might look like, based on the working understanding that reform may be an impossible endeavor and that the proletariat struggle may be achieved by revolution alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
